Guide to William J. Jedlick. Papers, 1967-1987.
Fenimore Art Museum
William J. Jedlick. Papers, 1967-1987.
This collection contains a rough draft and final copy of Jedlick's 1967 Masters Thesis, "Landscape Window Shades of the 19th Century in New York and New England" for the Cooperstown Graduate Program, Cooperstown, NY; a 22 page booklet entitled, Shades of History; and material related to the thesis and booklet. It also of correspondence, b&w and color photographs, publications and related material in which Jedlick is credited for his scholarship and photography.
.5 cu. ft.
Jedlick, William J., 1929-
Fenimore Art Museum Research Library 80 Lake Road Cooperstown, NY 13326
Coll. No. 448
Related Material
Theses J349 "Landscape window shades of the 19th century on New York State and New England," by William J. Jedlick.
747.5 L479 "Shades of History," by Ruth Lee.
NM-9.2008
Acquisition Information
Coll. No. 448 collection is open for research according to the regulations of Fenimore Art Museum Library.
Jedlick’s avid interest in painted window shades of the 19th century arose in 1967 from his search for a research topic while a student at the Cooperstown Graduate Program, Cooperstown, NY. His resulting Masters Thesis, "Landscape Window Shades of the 19th Century in New York and New England," started him on a trail of discovery that he pursued into the 1980s as he researched, consulted on, photographed, collected, appraised, and dealt in painted window shades, and lent them to museums for exhibition.
Biography/History
In 1968-1969, he consulted with Ruth Lee, Publicity Director for Joanna Western Mills, Co., Chicago, Illinois, on her 22 page booklet, Shades of History. Around that same time, Jedlick served as Associate Curator and Assistant Director of the Chicago Historical Society, and from about 1974-1987 as Regional Museum Curator for the National Park Service, N. E. Region, Philadelphia, PA. In 1987, Jedlick was also appraising antiques for W.J. Jedlick Appraisers, Philadelphia, PA. His first Masters Thesis, written while a student at DePaul University, Chicago, IL, in 1953, was entitled “Letters of Morris Sleight on the California Trail, 1850.
Jedlick, William J., 1929-; Lee, Ruth; Window shades--New York (State); Window shades--New England.; masters theses
This collection contains a rough draft and final copy of Jedlick's 1967 Masters Thesis, "Landscape Window Shades of the 19th Century in New York and New England" for the Cooperstown Graduate Program, Cooperstown, NY; a 22 page booklet entitled, Shades of History; and material related to the thesis and booklet.
Scope and Contents
It also contains correspondence requesting information about shades from Jedlick, and documenting Jedlick’s activity collecting, lending, donating, and selling window shades. Numerous b&w and color photographs (many of them labeled) in various formats, primarily of painted screens and building exteriors and interiors; and three publications and related material in which Jedlick is credited for his scholarship and photography are included. Finally, Jedlick's student papers on both Grecian and Hudson River School painting, 1967, and speeches on "The Past is Prologue to the Future" given at the Lake Forest (IL) Antique Show Press Luncheon, 1970, and on the publication release of Shades of History can be found in this collection.
- 448.1/1 Copyright registration for Masters Thesis, "Landscape Window Shades of the 19th Century in New York and New England, 1984
- 448.1/2 Correspondence, 1968 - 1987
- 448.1/3 Correspondence, Shades of History, 1968 - 1969
- 448.1/4 Student papers, speeches, 1967 - 1970
- 448.1/5 Photographs and negatives, and related correspondence (1 of 2), u.d.
- 448.1/6 Photographs and negatives, and related correspondence (2 of 2), u.d.
- 448.1/7 Publication, "Lake Forest Academy Antiques Show", June 1970, pp 32-37
- 448.1/8 Publication, "Old-House Journal," September/October 1987, pp 46-48
- 448.1/9 Publication, "Shades of History," 1969, 22 pp [FAMRL 747.5 L479]
- 448.1/10 Publication, "Window Fashions," August 1987, pp 14-22
- 448.1/11 Research material, window shades, u.d.
- 448.1/12 Thesis, "Landscape Window Shades of the 19th Century in New York State and New England" (1 of 2), 1967
- 448.1/13 Thesis, "Landscape Window Shades of the 19th Century in New York State and New England" (2 of 2), 1967